Alex Van Vleet

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Motivated full-stack software engineering graduate from Flatiron School with 2+ years of experience in the technology domain. Detailed and enthusiastic team player dedicated to efficiently resolving project issues in fast-pace environments. Ability and willingness to innovate and learn new technologies, quick learner, and passionate about development.





(630) 740-8023 vantero.dev@gmail.com 🙀 vantero.dev (im) linkedin.com/in/alex-van-vleet 💭 github.com/vantero9973



Work Experience

Freelancer @ TaskRabbit

Jul 2020 - Sep 2022 // Denver, CO

- Loaded, unpacked, and packed items, disassembled and assembled furniture for 500+ residential and commercial accounts per year
- · Assisted customers during the moves
- Developed teamwork and leadership skills from working with new people on a near daily basis

Fireproofer @ American Fireproofing Inc.

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020 // Denver, CO

- Positioned and fed ~5,000 lbs/day of materials into processing machines, by hand or by using automated equipment
- Tested machine parts every 1-2 hours to prevent breakdowns
- Disassembled and repaired pumps about once a day when clogged or malfunctioning

Insulation Technician @ USA Insulation

Jun 2018 - Jun 2019 // Carpentersville, IL

- Covered and lined structures with blown or injected forms of materials to insulate against cold, heat, or moisture
- · Employed wide variety of hand and power tools including hoists, drills, precision measuring instruments and electronic testing devices
- · Communicated operational issues and changes to supervisor on a daily basis

Skills

Programming Languages

Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS, SQL, Ruby on Rails

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Node.js, Express, Tailwind, **Bootstrap**

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Netlify, Material UI

Education

Flatiron School

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023 // Denver, CO Full-Stack Software Engineering course that teaches JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails

Central High School

2013 - 2017 // Burlington, IL

Interests

Traveling, climbing, snowboarding, cooking

Projects

Parts Undefined // Github | Demo

Travel app that allows users to browse popular destinations by country or continent and incorporates a blog, forum, and an e-commerce store for travel guides

- Employed the Ruby Bcrypt gem to add user authentication and password protection to the application
- Used Rails and SQL to create a database and a RESTful API backend
- Integrated Google Maps API with custom markers and positions for each country and destination
- Created a fully functional e-commerce store with Express and Stripe

Destination Picker // Github | Demo

App that allows users to select three inputs and have a random matching destination returned, as well as browse destinations by country and add points of interest

- Implemented a quiz in which a user can select three inputs and have a random matching destination returned
- Integrated react-simple-maps in order to allow users to click on a country and view its destinations
- Added CRUD capability to multiple components of the application

Pokémon Flatiron // Github | Demo

App that allows users to view and add Pokémon to the Hoenn Pokédex, as well as purchase Pokémon to add to their team

- · Implemented a front-end e-commerce store in which users can add selected Pokemon to cart
- Created and fetched from a custom API to hold, input, and store data
- Designed RESTful backend server enabling Pokemon to be stored persistently in the database